liveramp.com 2014-06-25

# LiveRamp | Web Privacy Policy

**LiveRamp Website Privacy Policy** ****

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to explain how data collected through this website is used. This Privacy Policy only applies to data collected through the LiveRamp.com website, or other websites operated by LiveRamp and linked to this website. For more information about LiveRamp’s broader privacy practices and models, including its placement of and access to online cookies, please go to <http://liveramp.com/data-privacy-policy>.

LiveRamp has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this website [LiveRamp.com](http://www.liveramp.com/).

TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at **privacy@liveramp.com**. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

**Collection And Use Of Your Information**

When you visit our websites, we may collect certain information from you. This information falls into two categories: 1) personal information you voluntarily supply when you log into our websites and 2) tracking information collected as you navigate our sites.

**Personal Information You Provide to Us:** **** We may retain and use for our business purposes (including to contact you, provide services to you, provide customer service and to send newsletters) personally identifiable information you provide to us such as your name, email address, company, and phone number.

**Tracking Information:** We may use technologies to track your use of our websites and tailor your web experience.

**Use of Cookies on Our Websites**

Cookies are small, unique strings of code stored on your computer that make it easier for you to use our site and help us improve site functionality and security. We may use both session cookies (which expire once you close your browser) and persistent cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them).

We use our own proprietary cookies, as well as cookies hosted by third party vendors. These cookies include non-personally identifiable information that allows advertisers and content owners provide a more customized web experience. They may be used to tailor ad content on our site as well as on sites you may visit in the future. They may collect data such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, and other clickstream data. (These first-party cookies, targeted at our customers and site users, are different from the cookies we deploy through the LiveRamp service, which may capture browser data including but not limited to your IP address, browser version, OS type, etc. We do not however collect information regarding clickstream, browsing behavior, or web page keywords. To learn about those cookies, go to <http://liveramp.com/data-privacy-policy>.

When you visit our web sites or open an email you have received from us, we or one of our ad partners may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. These cookies, which do not contain personally identifiable information, enable us to send you ads about our services, customize our services and gather analytics about our web traffic. Additionally, emails we send to you may contain a bit of code known as a "web beacon." This code helps us understand the time and date that a user has opened an email and when he/she has used a link within the email to visit a website, allowing us to collect analytics about our traffic, customize our services, and send you ads about our services. You can disable our web beacons by turning images "off" in your email client (e.g., Outlook, Outlook Express). Please see your email client for more information.

We may also use cookies to automatically collect information about your computer when you visit our sites, and automatically store it in log files. This may include the type of browser software you use, the operating system you are running, the website that referred you, and your Internet Protocol ("IP") address.

Your browser may permit you to reject or delete cookies, but this may prevent proper working of our website. If you want to opt-out of receiving some advertising cookies, please visit [http://aboutads.info](http://aboutads.info/ "http://aboutads.info") or [http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp.](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp "http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp")

**We May Disclose Your Personal Information As Follows:**

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

**Vendors and other Service Providers:** We may use third party service providers for network, security, email, and hosting services. Suppliers and service providers are required by contract to keep confidential the information received on our behalf, and may not use it for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for us.

**Disclosure Required By Law:** **** Under certain circumstances personal information may be subject to disclosure pursuant to judicial or other government subpoenas, warrants, or orders. Also when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request or to any other third party with your prior consent to do so. If we are ever legally compelled to disclose your personal information to a third party, we will notify you with the contact information we have unless doing so would violate the law or a court order.

**Disclosure of Non-personal information**

We may share with third parties or service providers non-personally identifiable information about your use of our website, which could include demographics, interests, and other online habits.

**Access, Control And Opt-Out**

Simple and Quick Opt-Out: You can opt out of our consumer databases at any time. Simply [**click here**](http://liveramp.com/opt_out "click here") to access our permanent opt-out tool. However, this opt-out tool does not apply to the data that you have provided to us through our website, to which the below options apply.

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove, or deactivate it by making the change on your settings page or by emailing our customer support at ****privacy@liveramp.com****.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter, we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us at **privacy@liveramp.com**.

**Other Important Information**

**Children's Privacy:** We do not knowingly collect personal information about children. Our systems are not designed for use by children under the age of 13. If we learn we have collected or obtained personal information of someone under 13, we will delete that information from our database. If you believe that this has occurred, please contact us at **privacy@liveramp.com** **.**

**Security:** We take the security of our data and client’s information seriously. We always take what we believe are reasonable precautions to protect against unauthorized access to our systems and to prevent data from being disclosed to unauthorized parties. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee absolute security.

**Business Transitions:** If we ever go through a business transition such as a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personal information and non-personal information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified in advance by email where possible, and we will post a prominent notice on our website. We will require an acquiring company or merger agreement to uphold the material terms of this privacy statement, including honoring requests for account deletion.

**Links to 3 rd Party Sites**

Our website includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of LiveRamp. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

**Blog / Forum**

Our website offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. You can request the removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, by contacting us at **privacy@liveramp.com**. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Changes to this Policy**

This Privacy Policy was last updated on March 18, 2014. We will provide notice for 30 days whenever this Privacy Policy is changed in a material way, presenting the old and new content. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**Contact Information**

If you have questions about this statement, please e-mail our privacy administrator at **privacy@liveramp.com** or contact us at:

Privacy Administrator, 667 Mission Street, 4th Floor San Francisco, CA 94105
